[
    {
        "id": 1,
        "section": 1,
        "description": "Features of the language, pronunciation, the alphabet, and simple greetings.",
        "questions" : [
            {
                "id": 1,
                "question": "Which is the correct lenition of \"Dear friend\"?",
                "choices": ["a cara", "a gcara", "a chara", "ah cara"],
                "correctAnswer": "a chara",
                "reason": "When addressing someone, add a séimhiú.",
                "state": "unanswered",
                "selectedAnswer": "",
                "category": "Eclipsis and Lenition",
                "isSubmitted": false
            },
            {
                "id": 2,
                "question": "How would you say \"the shoe\"?",
                "choices": ["tá bróg", "an bhróg", "ná bhróga", "mo bhróg"],
                "correctAnswer": "an bhróg",
                "reason": "Feminine nouns use the séimhiú.",
                "state": "unanswered",
                "selectedAnswer": "",
                "category": "Eclipsis and Lenition",
                "isSubmitted": false
            },
            {
                "id": 3,
                "question": "How would you say \"three cats\"?",
                "choices": ["trí chat", "tríuir chata", "ná cait trí", "an cait trí"],
                "correctAnswer": "trí chat",
                "reason": "Counting things of 2 to 6 takes a séimhiú.",
                "state": "unanswered",
                "selectedAnswer": "",
                "category": "Eclipsis and Lenition",
                "isSubmitted": false
            },
            {
                "id": 4,
                "question": "How would you say \"I am living in...\"?",
                "choices": ["Táim cóaní orm...", "Tá mé i mo cóaní i...", "Tá cóaní agam...", "Tá mé i mo chónaí i..."],
                "correctAnswer": "Tá mé i mo chónaí i...",
                "reason": "Possessive mo, do, agus a (my, yours, and his) get a séimhiú.",
                "state": "unanswered",
                "selectedAnswer": "",
                "category": "Eclipsis and Lenition",
                "isSubmitted": false
            },
            {
                "id": 5,
                "question": "How would you say \"You are in Dublin\"?",
                "choices": [
                    "Tá tú i mBaile Átha Cliath.", 
                    "Tá tú i Baile Átha Cliath.",
                    "Tá muid i mBaile Átha Cliath.", 
                    "Tá muid i Baile Átha Cliath."
                ],
                "correctAnswer": "Tá tú i mBaile Átha Cliath.",
                "reason": "Some prepositions (such as \"i\" meaing \"in\") are followed by the úrú. The city of Dublin does not have an article \"an\" meaing \"the\".",
                "state": "unanswered",
                "selectedAnswer": "",
                "category": "Eclipsis and Lenition",
                "isSubmitted": false
            },
            {
                "id": 6,
                "question": "Which is the correct conjugation of \"Your family\"?",
                "choices": [
                    "Tú teaghlach",
                    "Do teaghlach",
                    "A theaghlach",
                    "Do theaghlach"
                ],
                "correctAnswer": "Do theaghlach",
                "reason": "Mo (my), do (your), and a (his/her) get séimhiú.",
                "state": "unanswered",
                "selectedAnswer": "",
                "category": "Eclipsis and Lenition",
                "isSubmitted": false
            },
            {
                "id": 7,
                "question": "How would you say \"I am sitting\"?",
                "choices": [
                    "Tá mé i mo shuí",
                    "Tá mo shuí",
                    "Tá me i mo suí",
                    "Táimid inár suí"
                ],
                "correctAnswer": "Tá mé i mo shuí",
                "reason": "Mo (my), do (your), and a (his/her) get séimhiú. Literaly translation is \"I am in my sitting\".",
                "state": "unanswered",
                "selectedAnswer": "",
                "category": "Eclipsis and Lenition",
                "isSubmitted": false
            },
            {
                "id": 8,
                "question": "What is the correct translation for \"I was at work\"?",
                "choices": [
                    "Bí mé ag obair",
                    "Bhí mé ag obair",
                    "Táim ag obair",
                    "Tá mé i mo obair"
                ],
                "correctAnswer": "Bhí mé ag obair",
                "reason": "Regular verbs in the past tense get a séimhiú.",
                "state": "unanswered",
                "selectedAnswer": "",
                "category": "Eclipsis and Lenition",
                "isSubmitted": false
            },
            {
                "id": 9,
                "question": "What is the correct translation for \"Will you be there\"?",
                "choices": [
                    "An beidh tú ann?",
                    "An mbeidh tú ann?",
                    "An bhfuil tú ann?",
                    "An gbeidh tú ann?"
                ],
                "correctAnswer": "An mbeidh tú ann?",
                "reason": "Questions in future tense get an úrú.",
                "state": "unanswered",
                "selectedAnswer": "",
                "category": "Eclipsis and Lenition",
                "isSubmitted": false
            },
            {
                "id": 10,
                "question": "What is the correct translation for \"Our home?\"",
                "choices": [
                    "Ár gteach",
                    "Ár teach",
                    "Ár dteach",
                    "Ár theach"
                ],
                "correctAnswer": "Ár dteach",
                "reason": "Possessions for our, your, and plural get an úrú.",
                "state": "unanswered",
                "selectedAnswer": "",
                "category": "Eclipsis and Lenition",
                "isSubmitted": false
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "section": 2,
        "description": "Numbers and times, counting things, articles and animals, the bí verb and the weather, likes, dislikes and food.",
        "questions" : [
            {
                "id": 1,
                "question": "How would you say the nuber \"eleven\"?",
                "choices": ["a haon dhéag", "éag a haon", "a haon ó", "a dhéag amháin"],
                "correctAnswer": "a a haon déag",
                "reason": "No séimhiú on eleven.",
                "state": "unanswered",
                "selectedAnswer": "",
                "category": "Numbers and times",
                "isSubmitted": false
            },
            {
                "id": 2,
                "question": "Translate \"Tá sé a leathuar tar éis a haon\".",
                "choices": ["It is five o'clock", "It is quarter past one", "It is quarter to one", "It is half past one"],
                "correctAnswer": "It is half past one",
                "reason": "\"Leathuar\" means half an hour, \"tar éis\" is after.",
                "state": "unanswered",
                "selectedAnswer": "",
                "category": "Numbers and times",
                "isSubmitted": false
            },
            {
                "id": 3,
                "question": "How would you say \"now\"?",
                "choices": ["anois", "arís", "ann", "ansin"],
                "correctAnswer": "anois",
                "reason": "Other answers are \"again\", \"there\", and \"then\".",
                "state": "unanswered",
                "selectedAnswer": "",
                "category": "Numbers and times",
                "isSubmitted": false
            },
            {
                "id": 4,
                "question": "How would you say \"I am living in...\"?",
                "choices": ["Táim cóaní orm...", "Tá mé i mo cóaní i...", "Tá cóaní agam...", "Tá mé i mo chónaí i..."],
                "correctAnswer": "Tá mé i mo chónaí i...",
                "reason": "Possessive mo, do, agus a (my, yours, and his) get a séimhiú.",
                "state": "unanswered",
                "selectedAnswer": "",
                "category": "Numbers and times",
                "isSubmitted": false
            },
            {
                "id": 5,
                "question": "How would you say \"in the afternoon\"?",
                "choices": [
                    "ar maidin", 
                    "sa trathnóna", 
                    "san oíche",
                    "ar an trathnóna"
                ],
                "correctAnswer": "sa trathnóna",
                "reason": "\"sa\" means \"in the\" in this context.",
                "state": "unanswered",
                "selectedAnswer": "",
                "category": "Numbers and times",
                "isSubmitted": false
            },
            {
                "id": 6,
                "question": "Cé mhéad leabhar?",
                "choices": [
                    "dó leabhair",
                    "dhá leabhair",
                    "dhá leabhar",
                    "dó leabhar"
                ],
                "correctAnswer": "dhá leahbar",
                "reason": "The word for two things is \"dhá\" and the noun remains singular",
                "state": "unanswered",
                "selectedAnswer": "",
                "category": "Numbers and times",
                "isSubmitted": false
            },
            {
                "id": 7,
                "question": "How would you say \"19 houses\"?",
                "choices": [
                    "naoi dteach déag",
                    "naoi dteach dhéag",
                    "naoi theach déág",
                    "naoi theach dhéag"
                ],
                "correctAnswer": "nao dteach déag",
                "reason": "17-19 get an urú",
                "state": "unanswered",
                "selectedAnswer": "",
                "category": "Numbers and times",
                "isSubmitted": false
            },
            {
                "id": 8,
                "question": "How would you say \"16 houses\"?",
                "choices": [
                    "sé theach dhéág",
                    "sé theach déag",
                    "sé dteach déag",
                    "sé dteach dhéág"
                ],
                "correctAnswer": "sé theach déag",
                "reason": "11-16 get a séimhiú",
                "state": "unanswered",
                "selectedAnswer": "",
                "category": "Numbers and times",
                "isSubmitted": false
            },
            {
                "id": 9,
                "question": "Translate \"seacht mbosca dhéag\".",
                "choices": [
                    "seven boxes",
                    "seventeen boxes",
                    "seventy boxes",
                    "seven hundred boxes"
                ],
                "correctAnswer": "seventeen boxes",
                "reason": "direct translation",
                "state": "unanswered",
                "selectedAnswer": "",
                "category": "Numbers and times",
                "isSubmitted": false
            },
            {
                "id": 10,
                "question": "How would you say \"10 pens\"?",
                "choices": [
                    "deich peann",
                    "peann deich",
                    "deich bheann",
                    "deich bpeann"
                ],
                "correctAnswer": "deich bpeann",
                "reason": "7-10 get an úrú.",
                "state": "unanswered",
                "selectedAnswer": "",
                "category": "Numbers and times",
                "isSubmitted": false
            }
        ]
    }
]